Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Health and Estate Materials, 1936-91; Series VIII; 3.15; (8 boxes)
  - ESTATE
    - Memorial program: MW, 1988 Nov 3 (Box 195, Folder 2237)
    - "MW's Important Info.", 1936-86 (Box 195, Folder 2238)
      Includes letter from LW to MW [1986], clippings, and note by GW
    - Notebook listing contents of MW's library, n.d. (Box 195, Folder 2239)
    - Notes by Anatole Pohorilenko, ca. 1987-88 (Box 195, Folder 2240)
    - Notes by MW, n.d. (Box 195, Folder 2241)
    - Obituaries: GW, 1987 Feb (Box 195, Folder 2242)
    - Obituary: MW, 1988 Aug 15 (Box 195, Folder 2243)
    - Property invoice of decedent: MW, 1988 Aug 14 (Box 195, Folder 2244)
    - Receipts for household expenses, 1988 (Box 195, Folder 2245)
    - Receipts for mail, 1988 (Box 195, Folder 2246)
    - Receipts for storage rental, 1987 (Box 195, Folder 2247)
    - Report draft on MOMA, annotated with historical notes by MW and Anatole Pohorilenko, 1986 (Box 196, Folder 2248)
    - Safe deposit box keys, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 2249)
    - Stationery: MW, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 2250)
    - Anatole Pohorilenko's files
      - "re: Agreement with Hartman & Craven", 1988-89 (Box 196, Folder 2251)
      - "re: Assets", 1988 (Box 196, Folder 2252)
      - "Balaam", 1988 (Box 196, Folder 2253)
      - "re: Book Appraisal", 1987-88 (Box 196, Folder 2254)
      - "Debo Clark", 1942-87 (Box 196, Folder 2255)
        Includes journal page and fragment of letter by GW
      - "Consignments", 1985-87 (Box 196, Folder 2256)
      - "Faherty: AP's Power of Attorney", 1987 (Box 196, Folder 2257)
      - "Faherty: McCrackens", 1987-88 (Box 196, Folder 2258)
      - "Faherty: MW's Will", 1986, 1988 (Box 196, Folder 2259)
      - "Robert Frash", 1987 (Box 196, Folder 2260)
      - "Hugh Ford", 1987-88 (Box 196, Folder 2261)
      - "The Furniture 'business' at Hay-Meadows", 1987 (Box 196, Folder 2262)
      - "Furniture Appraisal", 1988 Nov (Box 196, Folder 2263)
      - "re: GW's estate", 1989-90 (Box 196, Folder 2264)
      - "re: Hartman & Craven: Gary Kissin", 1988-89 (Box 196, Folder 2265)
      - "Meyner & Landis: Matters pertaining to Glenway's estate", 1987-89 (Box 197, Folder 2266)
      - "Monroe's Hospital Folder", 1987 (Box 197, Folder 2267)
      - "Monroe's Papers: VITA", 1980-88 (Box 197, Folder 2268)
      - "re: MW's & GW's papers at the Beinecke Library, Yale University", 1988 (Box 197, Folder 2269)
      - "Notes from Bill Shepherd", n.d. (Box 197, Folder 2270)
      - "John Stevenson", 1987-88 (Box 197, Folder 2271)
      - "re: Stocks", 1988 (Box 197, Folder 2272)
      - "re: Taxes", 1988-90 (Box 197, Folder 2273)
      - "re: 251 E. 51st St. Appraisal", 1980, 1988 (Box 197, Folder 2274)
      - "Universities interested in GW's and MW's Papers", 1987-88 (Box 197, Folder 2275)
      - "Lloyd Wescott", 1980-88 (Box 197, Folder 2276)
      - "Robert Wilson", 1986-87 (Box 197, Folder 2277)
- Museum of Modern Art Records (MOMA), 1929-88; Series IX; 22.89; (56 boxes)
  Series VII, Photographs, consists of thirteen subseries, which are arranged chronologically and alphabetically.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Office files: "Personal Correspondence"
      - "A", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2278)
      - "B", ca. 1955-58 (Box 198, Folder 2279)
      - "C", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2280)
      - "D", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2281)
      - "E", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2282)
      - "F", ca. 1957-58 (Box 198, Folder 2283)
      - "G", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2284)
      - "H", ca. 1954-58 (Box 198, Folder 2285)
      - "I", 1957 (Box 198, Folder 2286)
      - "J", ca. 1957-58 (Box 198, Folder 2287)
      - "K", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2288)
      - "L", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2289)
      - "M", ca. 1954-58 (Box 198, Folder 2290)
      - "N", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2291)
      - "O", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2292)
      - "P", ca. 1956-58 (Box 198, Folder 2293)
      - "R", ca. 1956-58 (Box 199, Folder 2294)
      - "S", ca. 1956-58 (Box 199, Folder 2295)
      - "T", ca. 1957-58 (Box 199, Folder 2296)
      - "U", ca. 1958 (Box 199, Folder 2297)
      - "V", 1953-58 (Box 199, Folder 2298)
      - "W", ca. 1956-58 (Box 199, Folder 2299)
      - "Y", 1957-58 (Box 199, Folder 2300)
      - "Z", 1958 (Box 199, Folder 2301)
    - Office files: "General Correspondence"
      - "A", 1959-67 (Box 199, Folder 2302)
      - "B", 1959-67 (Box 199, Folder 2303)
      - "C", 1959-67 (Box 199, Folder 2304)
      - "D", 1960-67 (Box 199, Folder 2305)
      - "E", 1959-67 (Box 199, Folder 2306)
      - "F", 1959-67 (Box 199, Folder 2307)
      - "G", 1961-67 (Box 200, Folder 2308)
      - "H", 1959-67 (Box 200, Folder 2309)
      - "I", 1959-64 (Box 200, Folder 2310)
      - "J", 1959-65 (Box 200, Folder 2311)
      - "K", 1959-67 (Box 200, Folder 2312)
      - "L", 1959-65 (Box 200, Folder 2313)
      - "Mc.", 1960-63 (Box 200, Folder 2314)
      - "M", 1959-67 (Box 200, Folder 2315)
      - "N", 1954-66 (Box 200, Folder 2316)
      - "O", 1959-61 (Box 200, Folder 2317)
      - "P", 1959-67 (Box 200, Folder 2318)
      - "R", 1958-67 (Box 200, Folder 2319)
      - "S", 1955-67 (Box 200, Folder 2320)
      - "T", 1959-67 (Box 201, Folder 2321)
      - "U", 1954-60 (Box 201, Folder 2322)
      - "V", 1959-67 (Box 201, Folder 2323)
      - "W", 1959-67 (Box 201, Folder 2324)
      - "Y", 1959-60 (Box 201, Folder 2325)
      - "Z", 1960-67 (Box 201, Folder 2326)
      - "Correspondence with museums", ca. 1953-55 (Box 201, Folder 2327)
    - Office files: Special Categories
      - "Altercations", 1957-58 (Box 202, Folder 2328)
      - "Bindings DR. ERNST HAUSWEDELL", 1962 (Box 202, Folder 2329)
      - "Collections", 1954-59 (Box 202, Folder 2330)
      - "Collections 1960", 1950-66 (Box 202, Folder 2331)
      - "Confidential Memoranda", 1959-66 (Box 202, Folder 2332)
      - "d'Harnoncourt Chair", 1974 Apr 22 (Box 202, Folder 2333)
      - "Europe", 1952 (Box 202, Folder 2334)
      - "I. P. P. - India", 1954-59 (Box 202, Folder 2335)
      - "India", 1958-59 (Box 202, Folder 2336)
      - "India", 1974-75 (Box 202, Folder 2337)
      - "India Correspondence", 1954-56 (Box 202, Folder 2338-2339)
      - "Letters", 1938-41 (Box 202, Folder 2340)
      - "Loans from Museum Collection", 1957-67 (Box 202, Folder 2341)
      - "Mr. M. Wheeler's Cocktail Partys", 1960-66, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 2342)
      - "MOMA Strike - '73", 1973 (Box 202, Folder 2343)
      - "Museum of Modern Art", 1935-38 (Box 202, Folder 2344)
      - "Offers to MMA (Works of Art)", 1945-59 (Box 202, Folder 2345)
      - "Offers to MOMA (Works of Art)", 1960-66 (Box 202, Folder 2346)
      - "Personal Letters", 1953-69 (Box 202, Folder 2347)
      - "Staff Information", 1954-69 (Box 202, Folder 2348)
      - "Trustee File", 1965-66 (Box 202, Folder 2349)
    - Loose Correspondence: Alphabetical
      - "A" general, 1942-79 (Box 203, Folder 2350)
      - American Federation of Arts, 1958-85 (Box 203, Folder 2351)
      - Amor, Ines, 1973 May 28 (Box 203, Folder 2352)
      - Anthony, William, 1970 (Box 203, Folder 2353)
      - Archey, Gilbert, 1966 Jun 6 (Box 203, Folder 2354)
      - Auchincloss, Lily, 1987 Feb 18 (Box 203, Folder 2355)
      - "B" general, 1965-83, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2356)
      - Barbier-Müller, Monique, 1983 (Box 203, Folder 2357)
      - Barnes, Albert, 1951 May 9 (Box 203, Folder 2358)
      - Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1938-67, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2359)
      - Boulton, Alfredo, 1968 Aug 7 (Box 203, Folder 2360)
      - Britton, Coburn, 1965 Apr 20 (Box 203, Folder 2361)
      - Bunshaft, Gordon, 1974 Dec 11 (Box 203, Folder 2362)
      - Burden, William A. M., 1958-63 (Box 203, Folder 2363)
      - "C" general, 1938-87 (Box 203, Folder 2364)
      - Castleman, Riva, 1981 (Box 203, Folder 2365)
      - Chadwick, E. G., 1943 Jan 8 (Box 203, Folder 2366)
        with copy of draft of scenario for "Ode or Les Phènomènes de la Nature" by Pavel Tchelitchew, holograph, photocopy
      - Cross, Page, 1969-73 (Box 203, Folder 2367)
      - Crowninshield, Frank, 1938 Nov 23 (Box 203, Folder 2368)
      - "D" general, 1945-77 (Box 203, Folder 2369)
      - d'Harnoncourt, René, 1948-67 (Box 203, Folder 2370)
      - Dingelstedt, Kurt, 1955 (Box 203, Folder 2371)
      - Dunoyer de Segonzac, André, 1967 Mar 2 (Box 203, Folder 2372)
      - Duthuit, Marguerite, 1965-67 (Box 203, Folder 2373)
      - "E" general, 1942-[78] (Box 203, Folder 2374)
      - Eliot, T. S., 1950 Sep 29 (Box 203, Folder 2375)
      - "F" general, 1969-80 (Box 203, Folder 2376)
      - Fourcade, Xavier, 1970 Nov 24 (Box 203, Folder 2377)
      - Franc, Helen, 1960-77 (Box 203, Folder 2378)
      - Frasconi, Antonio, 1963 (Box 203, Folder 2379)
      - "G" general, 1948-87, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2380)
      - Goodyear, A. Conger, 1937-38 (Box 203, Folder 2381)
      - Green, Wilder, 1971 Aug 11 (Box 203, Folder 2382)
      - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1942 Oct 28 (Box 203, Folder 2383)
      - "H" general, 1943-80 (Box 203, Folder 2384)
      - Howard, Richard, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2385)
        includes English translation of essay by André Malraux
      - "I" general, 1965-80 (Box 203, Folder 2386)
      - "J" general, 1966-71, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2387)
      - Janis, Sidney, 1969-73 (Box 203, Folder 2388)
      - "K" general, 1942-78, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2389)
      - "L" general, 1965-86, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 2390)
      - Lieberman, William, 1968-78 (Box 203, Folder 2391)
      - Lowry, Bates, 1969 (Box 203, Folder 2392)
      - "M" general, 1949-86 (Box 203, Folder 2393)
      - McCray, Porter, 1947-61 (Box 204, Folder 2394)
      - McDermott, Eugene; McDermott, Margaret, 1972-73 (Box 204, Folder 2395)
      - Marshall, Philip C., 1971 Jul 10 (Box 204, Folder 2396)
      - Marx, Samuel, 1953 Nov 23 (Box 204, Folder 2397)
      - Matisse, Jean, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2398)
      - Mielziner, Jo, 1969 Jan 27 (Box 204, Folder 2399)
      - Moore, Henry, 1946 Nov 19 (Box 204, Folder 2400)
      - "N" general, 1945-86 (Box 204, Folder 2401)
      - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1956 (Box 204, Folder 2402)
      - "O" general, 1968-69 (Box 204, Folder 2403)
      - O'Keeffe, Georgia, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2404)
      - Oldenburg, Richard, 1973-82 (Box 204, Folder 2405)
      - Otero, Alejandro, 1968 Oct 10 (Box 204, Folder 2406)
      - "P" general, 1939-74, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2407)
      - Paley, William S., 1961-75 (Box 204, Folder 2408)
      - "Q" general, 1956 (Box 204, Folder 2409)
      - "R" general, 1943-85 (Box 204, Folder 2410)
      - Richards, Monawee, 1974-75 (Box 204, Folder 2411)
      - Rindge (Claflin), Agnes, 1938 (Box 204, Folder 2412)
      - Rockefeller, Blanchette, 1939-85 (Box 204, Folder 2413)
      - Rockefeller, David, 1968 May 3 (Box 204, Folder 2414)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1943-47 (Box 204, Folder 2415)
      - Rouault, Georges, 1938-47 (Box 204, Folder 2416)
      - "S" general, 1959-82, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2417)
      - Schoenborn, Florene, 1968 Aug 7 (Box 204, Folder 2418)
      - Sihare, Laxmi, 1967 Feb 2 (Box 204, Folder 2419)
      - Soby, James Thrall, 1951-72, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2420)
      - "T" general, 1971-74 (Box 204, Folder 2421)
      - Terrasse, Claude, 1968 Nov 29 (Box 204, Folder 2422)
      - "U" general, 1943-89 (Box 204, Folder 2423)
      - United Hospital Fund of New York, 1954-57 (Box 204, Folder 2424)
      - "V" general, 1950-68, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2425)
      - "W" general, 1950-69, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2426)
      - Whitney, John Hay, 1946, 1980 (Box 204, Folder 2427)
      - "Z" general, 1974, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2428)
      - Unidentified, 1950-87, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 2429)
    - Loose Correspondence: Third party
      - "Ann" to "Bernard", 1980 Oct 8 (Box 204, Folder 2430)
      - Weber, Max to "Miss Miller", 1938 Apr 10 (Box 204, Folder 2431)
    - Loose Correspondence: MOMA membership
      - MOMA members letters and invitations, 1948-86 (Box 204, Folder 2432-2434)
      - MOMA members letters and invitations, 1987-88, n.d. (Box 205, Folder 2435)
    - Memos
      - Memos addressed to MW, 1939-87 (Box 205, Folder 2436-2443)
      - Staff memos, 1968-82 (Box 205, Folder 2444-2446)
      - MW's phone memos and routing slips (Box 205, Folder 2447)
  - MOMA EXHIBITION MATERIAL
    - Airways to Peace (1943)
      - Preliminary outline, 1943 Feb (Box 206, Folder 2448)
      - Catalog text [by Wendell Wilkie], draft, typescript, corrected (Box 206, Folder 2449)
      - Catalog, 1943 Aug (Box 206, Folder 2450)
        Contains essay by MW
      - Clippings, 1943 Jul (Box 206, Folder 2451)
    - The Artist as Living History (n.d.)
      - Office file, 1931-52 (Box 206, Folder 2452)
        Includes letter from William K. Van Arsdale to MW [1931 Sep 8] and other correspondence
    - Bonnard, Pierre: Retrospective (1948)
      - Invitation, 1948 (Box 206, Folder 2453)
      - Clipping, 1948 (Box 206, Folder 2454)
    - Bonnard, Pierre: Memorial exhibition (1964)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2455)
      - Background texts, 1946-63 (Box 206, Folder 2456)
      - Budget estimate, 1963-64 (Box 206, Folder 2457)
      - Reproductions of works by Bonnard, 1964, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2458)
      - Photographs of works by Bonnard, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2459)
      - MW's working notebook with text drafts, 1964 (Box 206, Folder 2460)
      - Publicity blurb, draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 206, Folder 2461)
      - Biographical comments, draft pages, holograph, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, corrected (Box 206, Folder 2462)
      - Catalog text, draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2463)
      - Catalog text, draft pages, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 207, Folder 2464)
      - Catalog cover, proof, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2465)
      - Letter from Claude Terrasse, 1965 Jul 22 (Box 207, Folder 2466)
      - Article for Harper's Bazaar, draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1964 Oct (Box 207, Folder 2467)
      - Clippings, 1964 (Box 207, Folder 2468)
      - Office files, 1963-78 (Box 207, Folder 2469-2470)
    - Cezanne to Miro (1968)
      - Correspondence and planning memos, 1967-68 (Box 207, Folder 2471)
      - Checklists, 1967-68 (Box 207, Folder 2472)
      - Installation list for MOMA showing, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2473)
      - Insurance appraisal, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2474)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2475)
      - Notebook: "Notes by Lucy R. Lippard" with draft pages, notes and clippings, 1957, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2476)
      - Catalog text by MW, drafts, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, corrected, 1968 (Box 207, Folder 2477-2478)
      - Catalog text reprinted in Boletin de Museo (Argentina: Museo Nacional de Bellas Artes) (Box 207, Folder 2479)
      - Press releases, 1968 (Box 207, Folder 2480)
        includes introduction to exhibition by MW
      - Biographical sketch of MW, draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected and printed version, 1967-68 (Box 207, Folder 2481)
      - Notice for showing at the Center for Inter-American Relations, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2482)
      - Invitations, 1968 (Box 207, Folder 2483)
      - Copies of information re: Chile showing, 1968 (Box 207, Folder 2484)
      - Remarks by MW at opening of showing in Santiago, Chile, typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2485)
      - Clippings, 1968 (Box 208, Folder 2486-2487)
      - Compilation of reviews, 1968 (Box 208, Folder 2488)
      - Exhibition proposal citing "Cezanne to Miro", 1973 Oct 4 (Box 208, Folder 2489)
      - Office files, 1963-68 (Box 208, Folder 2490-2495)
    - Cezanne, Paul: Late Cezanne
      - Office file, 1970-75 (Box 208, Folder 2496)
    - Drawings (1944)
      - Catalog text, draft sections, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 208, Folder 2497)
      - Clippings, 1944 (Box 208, Folder 2498)
    - Drawings (1973-75)
      - Office file, 1971 Sep 28 (Box 208, Folder 2499)
    - Exhibition of American Contemporary Painting for India
      - Office file, 1956 (Box 209, Folder 2500)
    - Extraordinary Men
      - Blurb, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2501)
    - Four Americans in Paris: The Collections of Gertrude Stein and her Family
      - Office file, 1969 (Box 209, Folder 2502)
    - Hartley, Marsden
      - Foreword to catalog, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2503)
      - Clipping, 1944 Nov 20 (Box 209, Folder 2504)
    - Industrial Design exhibition for India
      - Office file, 1956-59 (Box 209, Folder 2505)
    - Industrial Design (1937)
      - Proposal, draft, typescript [incomplete], n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2506)
      - Office file, 1937 (Box 209, Folder 2507)
    - Latin American Artists (1972)
      - Office file, 1969-71 (Box 209, Folder 2508)
    - René Magritte (n.d.)
      - List of proposed artworks, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2509)
    - Maitres Populaires de la Réalité
      - Catalog text by Pierre Audry-Farcy, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2510)
    - Matisse, Henri: Exhibition Matisse (1951)
      - Exhibition catalog, annotated, 1951 (Box 209, Folder 2511)
        includes announcement of Matisse show at Albert Loeb & Krugier Gallery
    - Matisse, Henri: The Last Works of Matisse (1961)
      - Background notes and clippings, ca. 1955-62 (Box 209, Folder 2512-2513)
      - Notecards, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2514)
      - List of works requested, 1961 Jun 19 (Box 209, Folder 2515)
      - Wall label text draft, 1961 Oct 11 (Box 209, Folder 2516)
      - Catalog text drafts with notes, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1961 (Box 209, Folder 2517-2520)
      - "Reminiscences of Matisse" lecture announcement, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2521)
      - "Reminiscences of Matisse", office file, 1951, 1961 (Box 209, Folder 2522)
    - Matisse, Henri: Henri Matisse, 64 Paintings (1966)
      - Correspondence, 1966 Apr (Box 209, Folder 2523)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2524)
      - Catalog text drafts with notes, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 209, Folder 2525)
      - Biographical chronology for catalog, galley proof, 1966 (Box 209, Folder 2526)
      - Acoustiguide text draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2527)
      - Press releases for various Matisse exhibitions at MOMA, ca. 1931-65 (Box 209, Folder 2528)
      - Office file, 1951-66 (Box 209, Folder 2529)
        includes correspondence (with Lawrence Gowing)
    - Miro, Joan (1944)
      - Prospectus notes by Paolo Duarte, 1944 Mar 5 (Box 210, Folder 2530)
    - Modern Masters (1975)
      - Correspondence, 1975 Jan (Box 210, Folder 2531)
    - Modern Painters and Sculptors as Illustrators (1936)
      - Letters of introduction for MW, 1935 Jun (Box 210, Folder 2532)
      - Research notebook, 1935 (Box 210, Folder 2533-2534)
      - Exhibition labels (blank), n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2535)
      - Notes for lecture and catalog (Box 210, Folder 2536)
      - Clippings, 1936 (Box 210, Folder 2537)
      - Symposium agenda (Box 210, Folder 2538)
    - MOMA Publications (1962?)
      - Photographs of exhibition, [1962?] (Box 210, Folder 2539)
    - Paintings from New York Private Collections (1946)
      - Catalog, 1946 (Box 210, Folder 2540)
        with foreword by MW
    - Paintings from the Museum of Modern Art [at the National Gallery] (1963-64)
      - Office file, 1963-64 (Box 210, Folder 2541)
    - Picasso, Pablo: The Sculpture of Picasso (1968)
      - Office file, 1967 (Box 210, Folder 2542)
    - Power in the Pacific (1945)
      - Photograph, 1945 (Box 210, Folder 2543)
    - "Primitivism" in 20th Century Art (1984-85)
      - [Catalog text?], draft page, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2544)
      - Nametag: Monroe Wheeler, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2545)
      - Office file, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2546)
    - Responsive Eye (1965)
      - Office file, 1965 (Box 210, Folder 2547)
    - Rouault, Georges: Prints of Rouault (1938)
      - Woodcut by Maillol, 1939 (Box 210, Folder 2548)
      - Rouault issue of Le Point, 1943 (Box 210, Folder 2549)
      - Photographs of works by Rouault, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2550)
      - [Exhibition label?], n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2551)
      - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 210, Folder 2552)
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2553)
      - Catalog text, drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 210, Folder 2554)
      - Sketch of catalog cover, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2555)
      - Printed copy of catalog, corrected for second edition, 1938-42 (Box 210, Folder 2556)
      - Catalog text: "Technique", reprinted in catalog for show at Buchholz Gallery, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2557)
      - Invitations, 1938 (Box 210, Folder 2558)
      - Clippings, 1938-40 (Box 210, Folder 2559)
        includes reviews of other Rouault shows
      - Letter by MW to the editor of NYT with notes for revision of catalog, 1938 (Box 210, Folder 2560)
    - Rouault, Georges: Retrospective (1953)
      - Press release, 1953 Apr 1 (Box 211, Folder 2561)
    - Rouault, Georges: [unidentified exhibits]
      - Essay re: Rouault, draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2562)
      - [Notecards for essay / lecture?], n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2563)
    - Science and Art (n.d.)
      - Notes for proposal, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2564)
    - Soutine, Chaim: (1950)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2565)
      - Catalog text, draft sections, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected (Box 211, Folder 2566-2568)
      - Blurb for catalog, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2569)
      - Press release, draft pages, holograph, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2570)
      - Press release, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2571)
      - Invitation, 1950 (Box 211, Folder 2572)
      - Photographs of installation, [1950] (Box 211, Folder 2573)
      - "Soutine" article, printed version, Vogue, 1950 Nov 1 (Box 211, Folder 2574)
      - "The Expressionism of Soutine", draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2575)
      - "The Expressionism of Soutine", printed version, Harper's Bazaar, 1950 Nov (Box 211, Folder 2576)
      - Draft of letter from MW to Abrams [publishers], 1957 Apr 25 (Box 211, Folder 2577)
      - Review, The Nation, proof, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2578)
      - Clippings, 1950-51 (Box 211, Folder 2579)
      - Images by Soutine clipped from publications, ca. 1950-57 (Box 211, Folder 2580)
      - Notecards re: location of paintings, ca. 1954-57 (Box 211, Folder 2581)
      - Office files, 1949-53, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2582-2585)
    - [Surrealism?] (n.d.)
      - Catalog text page, draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2586)
    - Textiles and Ornaments of India (1956)
      - Press release drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2587)
    - Textiles circulating exhibition
      - List of shows with costs, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2588)
    - Turner, J. M. W.: Turner, Imagination and Reality (1966)
      - Background article (Box 212, Folder 2589)
      - List of paintings, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2590)
      - Photographs of works by Turner, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2591)
      - [Text for labels?] draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2592)
      - Notes for exhibition catalog, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2593)
      - Catalog texts, drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 212, Folder 2594)
      - Catalog text by Lawrence Gowing, galley proof, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2595)
      - Checklist of paintings, draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2596)
      - Publicity blurb, draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2597)
      - Exhibition flyer, 1966 (Box 212, Folder 2598)
      - Dinner seating list, 1966 Mar 21 (Box 212, Folder 2599)
      - Transcript of remarks made at opening reception, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2600)